<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Metapages Blog</title>
        <link>https://docs.metapage.io/blog</link>
        <description>Metapages Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 18:36:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metapages vs Binder]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.metapage.io/blog/comparison-with-other-tools-binder</link>
            <guid>https://docs.metapage.io/blog/comparison-with-other-tools-binder</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 18:36:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Documentation]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://docs.metapage.io/assets/images/1503191761-44d0749aebb0c2c29d6f1ec4b02115da.png" width="780" height="218" class="img_RZJ2"></p>
<p><a href="https://mybinder.readthedocs.io/en/latest/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Documentation</em></a></p>
<p>Binder is a way to share Jupyter notebooks. That means all the advantages and disadvantages of Jupyter notebooks.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="https://mybinder.readthedocs.io/en/latest/about/user-guidelines.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Binder</a> is meant for interactive and ephemeral interactive coding</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>BinderHub is a kubernetes-based cloud service that allows users to share reproducible interactive computing environments from code repositories.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Binder is a way to create reproducible interactive single compute environments, that serve Jupyter notebooks. You can share links to your binder instance, so that others can interact with your environment</p>
<p>However, there is no state management, so every binder instance is it’s own, since the source is the github repo.</p>
<p>There is no searchable catalogue of shared binders, and binders are not composable, they are single stand-alone instances.</p>
<p>The backend is built for kubernetes, which is the largest cluster manager by far, which is good, but you cannot simply plug in your own computer easily. Kubernetes is complex, so you need to have the support of a organization or highly technical individual to implement your own.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>